# Kayleigh "Kaleb" Bishop

Website: kalebishop.github.io Email: kaleb.bishop@colorado.edu GitHub: github.com/kalebishop

## Research Interests

I am interested in researching embodied computational models of human behavior, especially perceptual, linguistic, and social skills. Using knowledge of how humans perceive and operate on the world and the social beings around them can inform the creation of more intelligent, adaptive, and communicative systems. I am particularly interested in the potential application of these skills in the creation of socially assistive robotics. My other interests include human-robot interaction, natural language processing, artificial intelligence, and social learning across cultures.

### EDUCATION

#### University of Colorado at Boulder

Boulder, CO

Ph.D. in Computer Science, Advisors: Bradley Hayes & Alessandro Roncone

2020-Current

Yale University

New Haven, CT

B.S. in Cognitive Science, GPA: 3.92/4.00

2016–2020

- Concentration: Mind and Computation
- Thesis: "Towards Flexible Referring Expression Generation for a Collaborative Robot"
- Advisor: Brian Scassellati

# RESEARCH POSITIONS

#### University of Colorado at Boulder

Boulder, CO

Graduate Research Assistant

Fall 2020—Current

Human Interaction & Robotics Group and Collaborative AI and Robotics Lab

Yale University

New Haven, CT

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Yale Social Robotics Lab

Fall 2017—Spring 2020

# MENTORSHIP & TEACHING

•	Senior	Advising	Fellow at	Matriculate

2018—Current

Non-profit college advising for low-income high school students

• First-year Counselor at Yale University

2019—2020

Academic and residential advisor to first-year students

Yale Summer Session Counselor at Yale University

Summer 2019

Residential advisor to high school students in summer course program

• Computer Science Tutor at Yale University

2018-2019

Artificial Intelligence (CPSC470) and Data Structures & Programming Techniques (CPSC223)

• ONEXYS Mathematics Leader at Yale University

Summer 2017

Teaching college math fundamentals for incoming Yale students from low-income backgrounds

## SKILLS

## LANGUAGES

• **Programming:** Python, C/C++, Java, Lisp

• ML & CV libraries: PyTorch, Tensorflow, SciPy, OpenCV, Panda

• Robotics misc.: ROS, Webots, PyBullet, Flask

Spanish: Advanced IKorean: Intermediate II

# **PROJECTS**

- Grounded Natural Language for Collaborative Robotics; Undergraduate thesis project, 2019-2020. Social and communicative barriers between humans and robots limit human-robot collaboration from reaching the fluency and intuitiveness of human-human interactions. I helped to address this limitation by creating a cognitively-inspired semantic grounding model for language generation, based largely on recent work in psychophysics and psycholinguistics. I collected a corpus of original referring expression data from human participants and analyzed it to ensure the model was based on sound and consistent principles of human speech. This model allowed the robot to dynamically generate natural and informative requests for tools and other task-relevant objects from a human partner.
- Lights! Camera! Action! Learning a Lighting Policy for Robot Photography; CPSC490 Building Interactive Machines, Fall 2020. I collaborated with two other undergraduates to design an autonomous lighting adjustment system for a robot photographer. The system utilizes deep reinforcement learning to learn how to adjust studio lighting for portrait-taking based on the environment, camera pose, and subject pose.
- Network controller for the Baxter robot; Yale Social Robotics Lab, Spring 2019. Our lab worked in collaboration with a New York-based research laboratory on a novel cognitive architecture. My primary contribution was the creation of a Flask-based controller that allowed our local robot to receive data and instructions from our partner lab's remote server and translate them to environment models and joint commands for our local Baxter robot.
- Exploring robots as team-builders; Yale Social Robotics Lab, Fall 2018. I led data extraction and analysis for the preliminary phase of a mentor's project exploring the role of social robots as boosting team cohesion and psychological safety. I also assisted in planning the next round of trials, including adjusting the algorithmic approaches of the autonomous system.

#### SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

•	Chancellor's Fellowship, University of Colorado at Boulder	2020 – 2021
•	Magna Cum Laude, Yale University	2020
•	Honors in Cognitive Science, Yale University	2020
•	Richard U. Light Fellowship, Yale University	2018
•	Nathan Hale Scholarship, Yale University	2016-2017